Guide to the Records of the Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture RG.37.13
New York University Archives
- La Maison Française Sound Recordings, 1966-1999
  - Scarpetta, Guy: "Kundera, auteur français", March 9, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0184)
  - Grumbach, Antoine: "Ville et architecture: la dialectique des contraintes (in French and English)", March 30, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0185)
  - Prigent, Christian: "Lectures de textes", April 11, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0186)
  - Roger, Philippe: "Le dernier des libertins", April 18, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0187)
  - Ashbery, John and Martory, Pierre (écrivain, poète): "Bi-lingual reading of Martory's poems with translations by Ashbery", April 24, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0188)
  - Dupin, Marc Olivier: "Le Conservatoire et la Cité de la Musique", April 25, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0189)
  - Arrabel, Fernando: "Les titans se meurent...Vive le théâtre!" (Florence Gould Lecture), May 2, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0190)
  - Biancotti, Hector: "D'une Langue à l'autre: une expérience littéraire", May 3, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0191)
  - Nimier, Marie: "Comment j'ai écrit certains de mes livres", May 4, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0192)
  - Robbe-Grillet, Alain: "Littérature et correction politique", September 19, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0193)
  - Dramé, Kandioura: "Il était un fois...l'Afrique latine" (co-sponsored with Africana Studies Program), September 21, 1995 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0194)
  - Kurtz, Maurice: "Copeau: the Revolt of Dramatic Art in Paris and New York", October 10, 1995 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0195)
    Note on cassette says "incomplete"
  - Pennac, Daniel: "Lectures de textes et discussion en français", October 30, 1995 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0196)
  - Favier, Jean: "Une Bibliothèque pour le troisème millénaire" (Florence Gould Lecture), October 31, 1995 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0197)
  - Serres, Michel: "Science et culture à l'orée de ce siècle" (Florence Gould Lecture), November 2, 1995 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0198)
  - Ben Jelloun, Tahar: "Le rôle de l'écrivain dans les pays du sud", November 14, 1995 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0199)
  - Dezon Jones, Elyane: "An Annotated Reading of Murder chez Proust", November 21, 1995 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0200)
  - Roger, Philippe: "Roland furieux et amoureux: Barthes et le théâtre", November 28, 1995 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0201)
  - Rubidge, Bradley: "The Code of Reciprocation in Corneille's Heroic Drama" (recorded by Michael), November 30, 1995 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0202)
  - Sonnenfeld, Albert: "New Orleans and the French Connection", December 5, 1995 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0203)
  - Lubar, Robert: "Unmasking Pablo's Gertrude: Queer Desire and the Origins of Cubism", December 7, 1995 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0204)
  - Mercer, Valérie: "African-American Artists in Paris: 1945-1965", January 30, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0205)
  - Irelé, Francis Abiola: "Léopold Sédar Senghor: A Revaluation", February 6, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0206)
  - Howard, Richard: "Baudelaire and Whitman: A Missed Opportunity", February 12, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0207)
  - Federman, Raymond: "Lecture d'extraits de La Fourrure de ma tante Rachel", February 26, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0208)
  - Bury, Emmanuel, February 29, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0209)
  - Biet, Christian: "Tragique et tragédie classique", March 5, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0210)
  - Nicole, Eugène: "Retour à Saint Pierre", March 19, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0211)
  - Nancy, Jean-Luc: "Being with" (Florence Gould Lecture), April 9, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0212)
  - Lacoue-Labarthe, Philippe: "La Poétique de l'histoire" (Florence Gould Lecture, co-sponsored by the Department of German), April 11, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0213)
  - Ndiaye, Catherine: "Lecture de textes" (Co-sponsored with Africana Studies Program), April 16, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0214)
  - Scarpetta, Guy: "Réflections sur la critique", April 18, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0215)
  - Lacloche, Francis: "L'Etat, les villes, les entreprises: tous mécènes?", April 23, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0216)
  - Meddeb, Abdelwahab: "Dédale: Mondialité et transdisciplinarité", April 25, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0217)
  - Le Dantec, Jean-Pierre: "La Nouvelle architecture française", April 29, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0218)
  - Bujon de L'Estang, François: "La France, L'Europe et le nouveau partenariat transatlantique", May 1, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0219)
  - Heinan, Eglal: "Lui ou elle: les travestissements masculins et féminins dans L'Astrée", September 19, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0220)
  - Manet, Eduardo: "Lecture de textes", October 7, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0221)
  - Genette, Gérard: "Combray-Venise-Combray", October 8, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0222)
  - Artaud Colloquium: "Delirious Anthropology", October 18, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0223, 37-13.0224)
  - Gautrat, Patrick: "Les Grands axes de la politique étrangère de la France", October 22, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0225)
  - Ernaux, Annie: "Lecture de textes - Le Réel et l'intime", November 11, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0226)
  - Lestringant, Frank: "Argus à la sphère ou la mélancolie du cosmographe (XVIe siècle)", November 12, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0227)
  - Noël, Bernard: "Poésie et critique d'art", November 14, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0228)
  - Baudrillard, Jean: "L'Exponentielle et la masse critique" (Florence Gould Lecture), November 18, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0229)
  - Gengembre, Gérard: "Penser l'après-révolution: le moment 1800", November 19, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0230)
  - Salazar, Philippe Joseph: "Barthes et la séduction d'enseigner", November 21, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0231)
  - Peer, Shanny: "Tintin en Amérique: Popular Adventures in America Between the Wars", December 4, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0232)
  - Mainardi, Patricia: "Corot and Modernism", December 5, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0233)
  - Ivry, Benjamin, December 10, 1996 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0234)
  - Beaujour, Michel and Sieburth, Richard: "An evening of Maurice Scève", January 30, 1997 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0235)
  - Kaplan, Alice: "August 1944: Scenes from the Birth of Post- War France", February 3, 1997 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0236)
  - French Book Festival - Sollers, Philippe: "Introduction by Tom Bishop: L'Identité Française", September 8, 1997 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0237)
  - French Book Festival - Sollers, Philippe: Keynote lecture in French, September 8, 1997 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0238)
  - Zink, Michel: "Saint Bernard et la conversion du jongleur" (Florence Gould Lecture, co-sponsored by Medieval and Renaissance Studies Program), September 24, 1997 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0239)
  - Michon, Pierre: "Lectures de textes", October 2, 1997 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0240)
  - Roudinesco, Elisabeth: "Jacques Lacan; l'Histoire effacée" (French Theory in America Event), October 14, 1997 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0241)
  - Brombert, Victor: "Flaubert: Fiction, History, Revolution" (Andrew Dulau Lecture), October 21, 1997 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0242)
  - Dallenbach, Lucien: "La Mosaïque en art et littérature: de Balzac à Claude Simon", October 23, 1997 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0243)
  - Gaillard, Françoise: "On Barthes", October 27, 1997 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0244)
  - Genette, Gérard: "Esquisse d'un parcours", November 3, 1997 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0245)
  - Nothomb, Amelie: "Lecture de textes", March 12, 1998 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0246)
  - Reut, Tita and Arman: "Lecture de poésie et dialogue entre le poète et l'artiste", February 26, 1999 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0247, 37-13.0248)
  - Sarraute Tribute at Maison Francaise, January 27, 2000 (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0249, 37-13.0250)